Guide to the Archives Information File, Section 1: Boxes 1-22
Archives Information File, Section 1: Boxes 1-22
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Information File, Section 1: Boxes 1-22
6047
Kheel Center
109 linear ft.
Records.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into five sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-22
Section 2: Boxes 23-43
Section 3: Boxes 46-66
Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Section 5: Boxes 89-101
Boxes 44-45 and 102-109 have not been inventoried at this time.
SUBJECTS
Form and Genre Terms:
Records.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this collection:
6047: Archives Information File
6047: Archives Information File, Section 2: Boxes 23-43
6047: Archives Information File, Section 3: Boxes 46-66
6047: Archives Information File, Section 4: Boxes 67-88
6047: Archives Information File, Section 5: Boxes 89-101
Boxes 44-45 and 102-109 have not been inventoried at this time.
CONTAINER LIST
- Box: 1, Folder: 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Understanding Testing: Purposes and Interpretations for Pupil Development, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Notes: Steps in Job-Tests Program, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Industrial Psychology, Inc.
  - Item 3: Notes: Job-Tests Program (24 Job Areas), 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Notes: Job-Tests Program (Development), 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Notes: Steps in Job-Tests Program, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Test Service Bulletin, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: The Psychological Corporation
    Notes: September, 1954
  - Item 7: Notes: Job-Tests Program (Development), 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Industrial Psychology, Inc
    Notes: Copy 2
  - Item 8: Short Employment Tests: A Battery of Three Tests for Use with Clerical Applicants; Verbal, Numerical, Clerical Aptitude, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: George K. Benett
  - Item 9: Design of Tests for Specific Selection Problems: The Importance of Identifying Critical Requirements and Measuring them Specifically, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Marion F. Shaycoft
    Notes: February 1957
  - Item 10: The Group Oral Test in Selecting Public Employees, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Roberta Scott
    Notes: October, 1950
  - Item 11: Psychological Testings, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Methods Engineering Council
    Notes: May-June 1956
  - Item 12: Pre-Employment Tests Save You Time and Money, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Raymond Thurow
    Notes: January, 1952
  - Item 13: Essential Characteristics of a Testing Program, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Educational Testing Service
  - Item 14: Using Aptitude Tests in Selecting Industrial Personnel, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Robert L. Peterson
  - Item 15: The Validity of Commonly Employed Occupational Tests, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Edwin E. Ghiselli
  - Item 16: The Development of a Test for Selecting Research Personnel, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: American Institute for Research
    Notes: January 1950
  - Item 17: Technical Appendices for the Development of a Test for Selecting Research Personnel, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 18: Job Qualification Inventory, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Keith Van Allyn
  - Item 19: Personnel Testing: A Field Check on the Current Status of Personnel Testing in 100 Organizations, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Forrest V. Routt, Jr.
    Notes: October, 1946
  - Item 20: Validation of a Physiological Test of Aptitude for Learning Social Motives, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Albert F. Ax
  - Item 21: What Research Says to the Supervisor: Using Personnel Tests, 1962; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Society for Personnel Administration
    Notes: January 1962
  - Item 22: Testing Applicants for Selection and Placement, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Metropolitan Life Insurance Company
  - Item 23: Testing Applicants for Employment, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 24: An Annotated Bibliography on Measurement and Evaluation, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: May 1955
  - Item 25: Psychological Testing for Small Business, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Joseph E. King
    Notes: July 1954
  - Item 26: Psychological Testing, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: May-June 1956, Copy 2
  - Item 27: Methods of Expressing Test Scores, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: January 1955
  - Item 28: Flanagan Aptitude Classification Tests, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Science Research Associates, Inc.
  - Item 29: How to Install a Personnel Testing Program, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 30: Notes: Job-Tests Program--In Brief, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 31: Notes: Steps in Job-Tests Program, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Box: 1, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Psychomotor Abilities in Rotary Pursuit Performance Under Two Methods of Practice, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: J. R. Hinrichs
- Box: 1, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Aptitude Testing: Guidelines and References, 1972; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: Stephen Berkley
    Notes: August 1972
  - Item 2: A Report on the Effect of Age, Education and Sex on the Personnel Test Scores, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: E. F. Wonderlic
  - Item 3: Performance Norms by Adults on Separate Forms of the Wonderlic Personnel Tests, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Box: 1, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Employment Testing: Guide Signs, Not Stop Signs, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: U.S. Commission on Civil Rights Clearinghouse
  - Item 2: How to Use a Wonderlic Personnel Test, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Box: 1, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Manual for Uses: Clerical Skills Tests, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Author: U.S. Department of Labor
    Notes: March 1968
- Box: 1, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Summary of Experiences with the Wonderlic Personnel Test: Brief Quotations from Reports in Journals, Periodicals, Magazines and Text Books, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Box: 1, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Testing of Minority Group Applicants for Employment, 1966; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Phyllis Wallace, Beverly Kissinger, and Betty Reynolds
    Notes: March 1966
- Box: 1, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: What Psychological Tests Contribute to Personnel Selection, 1966; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Robert N. McMurry
  - Item 2: What Research Says to the Supervisor: Using Personnel Tests, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Box: 1, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Selected Bibliography, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Charles F. Sproule, Edgar L. Yost
    Notes: February 1968
- Box: 1, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Size and Morale: A Further Study of Attendance at Work in Large and Small Units, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: The Action Society Trust
  - Item 2: Selected Bibliography on Non-Occupational Sickness Absenteeism Among Industrial Workers, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Committee on Medical Care for Industrial Workers of the Council on Medical Service and Council on Industrial Health
  - Item 3: Reducing Absenteeism Through Employee Education, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 4: Prolonged Non-Occupational Illness: A Nationwide Study Among Employed Persons, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Research Council for Economic Security
  - Item 5: Absenteeism and its Control, 1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: The Bureau of National Affairs, Inc.
  - Item 6: Absenteeism: An Analysis of the Problem, 1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Confederation of British Industry
    Notes: January 1970
  - Item 7: Absenteeism, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Merchants and Manufacturers Association
    Notes: September 24, 1954
  - Item 8: Absenteeism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Occupational Health Institute
  - Item 9: Report on a Survey of the Cost of Absenteeism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Benson Laboratories, Inc.
  - Item 10: Prolonged Non-Occupational Illness: A Nationwide Study Among Employed Persons, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 11: Absence from Work Due to Non-Occupational Illness and Injury: What is Labor Doing About it?, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Jerome Pollack
    Notes: January 24, 1956
  - Item 12: Size and Morale: A Preliminary Study of Attendance at Work in Large and Small Units, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: The Acton Society Trust
  - Item 13: Absence from Work: Incidence Cost and Control, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: British Institute of Management
  - Item 14: Working with People: Attendance Problem, 1959; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: The Bureau of National Affairs
    Notes: September 3, 1959
- Box: 1, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Absencja Chorobowa: I Jej Skutki Ekonomiczne Dla Gospodarki Nardowej, 1964; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Edward Wojewodkzki
    Language: Polish.
  - Item 2: Absenteeism and its Control, 1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Notes: June 1970
- Box: 1, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: What Companies are Doing to Control Absenteeism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Author: Dartnell Administrative Management
  - Item 2: Illness-Absences and Separations 1962: Special Release, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Author: Life Office Management Association
- Box: 1, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Crisis at the University of California: A Further Statement to the People of California, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: American Civil Liberties Union
    Notes: November, 1951
  - Item 2: Keeping Our Schools Free, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: H. Gordon Hullfish
  - Item 3: Freedom, the University and Adult Education, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Robert J. Blakely
    Notes: May 4, 1953
  - Item 4: Permit Communist-Conspirators to be Teachers?, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: United States Government Printing Office
  - Item 5: Academic Freedom and Civil Liberties of Students in Colleges and Universities, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: November 1961
  - Item 6: American Association of University Professors: Draft Statement by Committee "S" on Faculty Responsibility for the Academic Freedom of Students, 1965; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Student Academic Freedom Program
    Notes: March 22, 1965
- Box: 1, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Handle with Care, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: National Safety Council
  - Item 2: Inventory of Occupational Accident Prevention Activities, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: January 21, 1957
  - Item 3: Occupational Safety Posters, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 4: Accidents: How they Happen and How to Prevent them, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Ministry of Labour and National Service
    Notes: July 1953
  - Item 5: Industrial Accident Prevention, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 6: Guide to Community Safety Programs, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: James P. Mitchell
  - Item 7: Guidelines for Safety, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: United States Treasury Department
  - Item 8: Health and Miscellaneous Hazards at Metal and Nonmetallic Mines, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Bureau of Mines
  - Item 9: The Fall Guy!, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 10: Get a Load of This!, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 11: Adapting the Job to the Worker, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Bernard Metz
  - Item 12: 1959 Directory of Occupational Safety Posters, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 13: Our State Safety and Health Laws, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Lois S. Gray
    Notes: March 1950
  - Item 14: One Out of Six, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Federal Safety Council
    Notes: April 1952
  - Item 15: Organization and Operation of the Division of Safety and Hygiene of the Industrial Commission of Ohio, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: James H. Fluker
  - Item 16: Machinists' Hand Tools, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 17: Don't Overlook Operator Safety in Press-Tool Design, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: L. A. Faulkner
  - Item 18: Five Minute Safety Talks for Foremen, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 19: Hand Tools, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 20: Butch Looks to You, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: United States Department of Labor
  - Item 21: Organizing for Safety in the Hospital, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: American Hospital Association
  - Item 22: Nitric Acid, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: U. S. Department of Labor
  - Item 23: Organizing for Safety in the Hospital, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 24: Nitric Acid, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 25: Safety in Foremanship, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 26: Teach Themto Lift, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: June 1949
  - Item 27: Safety Education in the School Shop, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: National Safety Council, Inc.
  - Item 28: Butch Learned the Hard Way, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 29: How to Prevent Accidents: Safety Briefs for Foremen and Supervisors, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Glenn L. Gardiner
  - Item 30: Getting Results from Safety Work: Facts for the Chief Operating Official, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 31: Safety in Foremanship, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 32: Labor Safety in Hungary, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 33: Organising Workplace Safety, 1963; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: John L. Williams
    Notes: May 1, 1963
  - Item 34: Electrical and Mechanical Hazards and Falls of Persons at Metal and Nonmetallic Mines, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 35: Accident Prevention and First Aid Suggestions, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: The Industrial Commission of Ohio
- Box: 1, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Construction Safety Requirements: Federal Highway Projects, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: U.S. Department of Transportation
  - Item 2: A Creative Approach to Safety, 1962; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: Florida Engineering and Industrial Experiment Station
    Notes: September, 1962
  - Item 3: A Practical Safety and Security Program for Small and Medium Size Plants, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: Theron F. Miller
  - Item 4: ABCs of the Job Safety and Health Act, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 5: The Consultative Approach to Safety, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 6: Control of Electrical Shock Hazards, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Box: 1, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Health and Safety Manual for Orders, Notices and Report Writing, 1975; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Author: United States Department of the Interior
    Notes: January 1975
  - Item 2: Fire Protection for the Safety Man, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 3: Prevenir Les Accidents De Travail, 1970; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Author: Federation Des Industries Belges
    Language: French.
- Box: 1, Folder: 17, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Inspection and Maintenance of Power Presses, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 2: Labor Safety in Soviet Industry, 1965; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Central Intelligence Agency
    Notes: March 1965
  - Item 3: The Factories Act (N.I.) 1965; A Short Guide, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Northern Ireland Ministry of Health and Social Services
  - Item 4: The Inorganic Acids, 1964; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 5: Unfallverhutung Auch Fur Auslandische Mitarbeiter, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Aulis Verlag Deubner & Co.
    Language: German.
- Box: 1, Folder: 18, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: On the Job Slaughter: A National Shame, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 2: Management Ideas that Promote Safety; Two Untypical Approaches to the Problem of Getting People Interested in Safety from Continental Baking Company, Southwestern Bell Telephone, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Author: Dartnell Office Administration
- Box: 1, Folder: 19, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Personal Protective Equipment for Employees in Industry, 1965; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: American Medical Association
    Notes: April, 1965
  - Item 2: Personal Protective Equipment, 1961; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Box: 1, Folder: 20, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: The Challenge to Supervisors: Making Young Workers Safe Workers, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 2: Safety in Your Future, 1966; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 3: Hearings Before Subcommittee No. 5 of the Committee on the District of Columbia House of Representatives Relating to Industrial Safety in the District of Columbia, 1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Author: The District of Columbia House of Representatives
    Notes: April 28 and May 4, 1967
  - Item 4: Status of Safety Standards, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 5: State Safety Code Comparison Studies, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 6: State Safety Code Comparison Studies, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Box: 1, Folder: 21, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Talk Topics: A Supervisor's Guide for Safety Discussions, 1963; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Author: Clark Woodward
  - Item 2: Works Safety Committees in Practice--Some Case Studies, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Author: Ministry of Labour
- Box: 1, Folder: 22, Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: List of Periodicals Abstracted, 1968; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Author: International Occupational Safety and Health Information Centre
    Language: English; French; German.
  - Item 2: Publications Dealing With Occupational Safety and Health, 1967; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Author: International Labour Office
- Box: 1, Folder: 23, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Safety Clauses in Collective Bargaining Agreements in the Federal Service, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Box: 1, Folder: 24, Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: International Labour Convention No. 115, Concerning the Protection of Workers against Ionising Radiations, Adopted by the General Conference of the International Labour Organisation During its Forty-Fourth Session, 1960; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Author: International Labour Organisation
    Notes: June 22, 1960
  - Item 2: Report of Conferences on Industrial Plant Protection, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Author: New Jersey Department of Public Instruction
- Box: 2, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: ABCs of the Job Safety and Health Act; The Law in Brief, Checklists, Text of the Act, 1971; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: State Occupational Safety and Health Legislation, 1964; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Notes: April 1964
  - Item 3: Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, Public Law 91-596, 1971; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Recordkeeping Requirements Under the Williams-Steiger Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Author: House of Representatives
  - Item 6: Highlights 1967-68 State Safety Code Activity, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Comparison of State Safety Codes with ASA-Fixed Ladders, A14.3-1956, 1963; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Notes: Poster Graph, October 1963
- Box: 2, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The Industrial Safety Act, 1964, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Author: Mr. Rowntree
- Box: 2, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Offices, Shops and Railway Premises Act 1963, Chapter 41, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Author: Her Majesty's Stationery Office
- Box: 2, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Minnesota Regulations Relating to Industrial Safety, 1964 Edition, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Author: Department of Labor and Industry
- Box: 2, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Report of the Governor's Advisory Committee on the Health & Safety of Workers in the State of New Jersey, 1962; Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Author: Governor's Advisory Committee of New Jersey
- Box: 2, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Statutes of Nova Scotia - 1965: An Act Respecting Industrial Safety Act, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Notes: March 30, 1965
- Box: 2, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Report to the President: Mobilizing Leadership for a Safety Breakthrough, 1964; Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Author: The President's Conference on Occupational Safety
    Notes: June 23, 24, and 25, 1964
- Box: 2, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Off-the-Job Accidents, 1938; Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Box: 2, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Heroes, Homework, and Industrial Growth, 1966; Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Author: William F. Whyte and Robert R. Braun
- Box: 2, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Social Reconstruction in the Newly-Independent Countries of East Africa, 1965; Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Author: United Nations
- Box: 2, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Industrial Estates in Africa, 1965; Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Box: 2, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Race, Culture and Personality, 1959; Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Author: Simon Biesheuvel
  - Item 2: Soweto: Johannesburg's African City, 1967; Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Author: Ellen Hellmann
  - Item 3: Introduction to South Africa; Basic Facts and Figures, 1968; Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Author: Muriel Horrell
    Notes: April 1968
- Box: 2, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: The Scope for Investment in South Africa, 1964; Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Author: Union Acceptances Limited
    Notes: April, 1964
  - Item 2: Poverty in Perspective, 1967; Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Author: Sheila T. van der Horst
    Notes: April 1967
  - Item 3: Some Aspects of the South African Industrial Revolution, 1951; Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Author: H.J. Van Eck